Guide to the ARS Miscellany ARS.0099
Archive of Recorded Sound
ARS Miscellany
1899-2005
ARS.0099
4 boxes
Archive of Recorded Sound
Transfers and copies on optical media, radio programs, research materials, transcripts, scrapbooks, and other miscellany from the shelves of the Archive of Recorded Sound.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The title for this artificial collection is self-explanatory. While there are some audio recordings here (mostly radio programs), this collection is largely paper-based. The related collection ARS Audiotape Collection (ARS0070) is entirely tape-based, and the few recordings found here are of a more recent vintage and almost all on optical disc media. Included is research material, photographs, transcripts, a scrapbook, one DVD-R, and a box of realia (largely equipment and promotional items). Items in folders 1-5 in Box 1 have been cataloged individually, and much more information can be found about them in Stanford's on-line catalog. Items will be continually added to this collection, and this finding aid will be revised as needed.
- Matías Bombal - Swingin' At The Cotton Club, Classic Jazz and Swing, radio program from KXJZ, 2005; 2 CD-Rs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains two CD-Rs and some paper documentation from a public radio program from 2005. On one compact disc, Bombal relates the story of the Cotton Club in New York City, with studio recordings of artists and songs introduced and performed at the club. He also presents a broadcast by Hellmut H. Hellmutt of the Reichs-Rundfunkgesellschaft, a supplier of pre-recorded programs to radio stations in Germany of the midnight show of April 20-21, 1931. It is the only known complete broadcast from the original location of the Cotton Club on 142nd Street at Lennox Avenue in Harlem and among the earliest surviving sound documents of German radio. The broadcast was discovered in the vaults of Sony/BMG by archivist Michael Brooks. The last track on the disc is a copy of an excerpt from the news talk show Insight, in which Jeffrey Callison interviews Matías Bombal about the Swingin' at the Cotton Club program. The other compact disc is a production reference recording of Bombal interviewing Michael Brooks about his discovery. Excerpts of the interview were broadcast on KXJZ.
  Bombal, Matías, 1967-; Calloway, Cab, 1907-1994
- Clifford Brown Jr. - The Clifford Brown Story, radio program from KDIA, 2006; 5 CD-Rs (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Brown, Clifford
- Jim Cullum Collection Transfers and Documentation, 2004; 7 CD-Rs (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  Four folders of transfers and documentation on optical media related to the Jim Cullum Collection (ARS0036), likely overlapping with that collections' contents.
  Cullum, Jim
- Dmitri Dobkin Material, 1946-1947; 3 pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Dmitri (spelled here Dmitry) Dobkin, a singer and recording artist, was director of the Brooklyn Free Musical Society's School of Music. Material includes two pamphlets and a concert program.
  Dobkin, Dmitri
- Alexander Fried Material, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Fried was a music critic for the San Francisco Examiner. Material includes reprints of early phonograph leaflets, newspaper clippings of reviews, a press release from Philips-Mercury, a San Francisco Symphony Program from 1972, handwritten notes, and various notes related to Berg's Lulu.
- Ted Hallock - The Mystery of Artie Shaw, radio program from KBOO, 1998; 13 CD-Rs (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  Shaw, Artie, 1910-2004
- Jascha Heifetz, transfer for Deutsche Gramophon 477 627-1 (two copies), 2 CD-Rs; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Jascha Heifetz - Pianist/Composer. When You Make Love To Me; So Much In Love
- Ozzie Hilton Collection Photographs, 1930s; 9 photographs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Photographs separated from original donation. Featured are Tom Coakley (two images, one autographed to Hilton), Carl Ravazza, Al Bowlly, The Biltmore Trio (Paul Gibbons, Eddie Bush, Bill Seckler), Ray Noble, and Russ Columbo. All are promotional photographs.
- Edward Jabès Material, 1 folder; Jabès, Edward (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Jabès (1903-1983) was a professional singer based in Berkeley, California. Material includes class notes from c.1950, an insert for his LP French Songs From Medieval To Modern Times, a paper compiled and translated by Jabes titled Yvette Guilbert Columbia Recordings, and French sheet music with Guilbert on the cover.
- Russ Lambert - Bing Crosby Material, 1940-2004; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Russ Lambert (1918-2004) was a Bing Crosby enthusiast and record collector. Material includes a scrapbook and correspondence with record labels, dealers, collectors, and associates from 1940-1948, and chronicles the relatively early development of the Crosby discography. Also enclosed is a memorial notice and a photograph of a Heathkit color television from 1962.
  Crosby, Bing, 1903-1977
- Marian McPartland - Piano Jazz, radio program on NPR. Artie Shaw, with Richard Sudhalter, 2002-06; 1 CD-R; McPartland, Marian; Sudhalter, Richard M. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- James B. McPherson - Ernestine Schumann-Heink Research Material, 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Typewritten chronology and notes, handwritten notes, transcribed or photocopied newspaper articles
  Schumann-Heink, Ernestine, 1861-1936
- William R. Moran - Nellie Melba Lecture, 1990-01-14; 1 audiocassette and transcript; Moran, William R. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931
- Grover Sales - Imagining Buddy Bolden, radio program from KALW, 1997-09; 2 CD-Rs; Sales, Grover (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Bolden, Buddy, 1877-1931
- Cecil Taylor, All The Notes DVD, 2004; 1 DVD-R (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Features Cecil Taylor speaking about himself and about jazz and performing in various venues, with added commentaries about Taylor's music from other narrators.
  Taylor, Cecil, 1929-
- Fred Terman - Speech Transcript, West Coast Electronic Manufacturing Association Dinner, 1955-05-12; 1 folder; Terman, Fred, 1900-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Theater Records scrapbook, 1 scrapbook (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Scrapbook from an unidentified owner probably from the Los Angeles area, with clippings from theater, opera, and ballet programs, 1899-1919. Also some criticism. Venues include the Mason Opera House, Los Angeles Theatre, Columbia Theatre, Temple Auditorium, Macdonough Theatre, Hamburger's Majestic Theatre, Burbank Theatre, Alcazar, Shrine Auditorium, and a few from UC Berkeley's Greek Theatre. Performers include Schumann-Heink, Tetrazzini, De Rezke, Galli-Curci, Teyte, Harry Lauder, and actors Billie Burke and Tyrone Power.
- Harold Youngberg Material, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Youngberg was a classical music critic in the 1930s and 40s. Material includes a phonograph record log from 1943 with comments, and typewritten reprints of criticism from 1935-1936.
- Miscellaneous Objects (Box 4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Two record cleaning brushes (Decca, Pocatello Music Co.); Rockwalk/1995 Grammy Award toy tambourine; 1995 Grammy Awards/Guitar Center/Fender outsized guitar pick; Ampex coaster; two Robins tape splicers (one in box with instructions); Ampex demagnetizer; G. Bettini International Exposition Paris 1900 souvenir medals (from Moran Collection); B+K Precision 3020 Sweep/Function Generator (in box); Stax SR-5 Electrostatic Ear-speaker headphones (in box)